Okay, so I'm going to share my screen first of all, and I'm going to put in
more polls
so you can see you all.
Okay.
Okay, welcome everybody.
Thank you for coming.
I know it's a hectic day because it's holidays and, you know, there are a lot
of people can't make it, but I'm hoping that everybody will be able to catch up
.
And thank you so much to Paul for being here.
We love working with you, and we're so grateful for you to come and just talk
to us a little bit about things from your perspective, because I think it'll
really help so many girls, especially head about event next week, where you'll
be meeting people for the first time.
And so we've got a few slides that we're going to go through, we're just going
to ask Paul a few questions that have been given to us from our members, and,
and then go over a few tips that Paul and Georgia have and that they can talk a
little bit about.
And then at the end, if anyone wants to ask any questions for Paul or for
Georgia or any of us, and then they can ask any questions at the end and you
can put any, any questions in the chat as well if you don't want to do it
yourself just put them in the chat and I'll ask.
Okay, so, and Paul, would you like to introduce yourself.
Yeah, sure. So, there are one of two of you already actually know, and I'm
looking at who's actually already on as well I can see the Sammy's on there,
who I've shot with before and it was great fun.
And of course with yourself Cheryl.
So I have been a photographer, as you can see there on screen for over 20 years
.
And I've done all types of photography over that time. I've even run my own
studio at one point.
But I prefer the freedom of being able to actually just shoot where I want and
what I want, rather than being tied to a location.
I think it can be a bit more creative. And that's what the whole point is my,
my images are meant to be creative.
To be able to actually capture the real sort of the real essence of that person
.
I'd like to believe all my images are of a, they're all classy and not trashy,
because that's the whole point is you know I want to actually just sort of make
sure that you actually come away feeling good about it.
So I shoot all sorts of styles everything from fashion as you can see all the
way through to pay per view. And I shoot across all of the country. The one
that's on the screen at the moment that's actually who I shot that for one of
her pay per view pages.
And that's actually in her bathroom in her house so yeah it's pretty special
actually she had it made up especially for that so yeah it's just, I'm, I'm, I
would say this I'm nothing special it's just I actually enjoy what I do.
I enjoy meeting like minded people.
I, I wouldn't say I'm a diva when it comes to being a photographer.
But I do expect sort of when, when I'm shooting with people that they actually
sort of just listen every so often when I'm actually asking them to do things I
mean I'm asking if I'm asking from actually pose a certain way, then that's it
's for a reason.
And I just want to make sure they get the best possible images from me.
So, it might sound like sometimes I'm sort of preaching a little bit to them.
And if I am then I apologise but we get, we want to get the best out of that
day. We want to get the best out of those images.
And I want them to actually help you to feel good about yourselves and also to
be able to actually get yourself additional works, which is the whole point.
Thank you, Paul and just to add to that like you've obviously been at a couple
of our shoots and, and, and we've shot together separately from that.
And I've seen how you like really made the girls feel so, you know, at ease,
especially new girls who haven't done it before.
And you know you've asked them all questions about what they like and you know
what they want and yeah so it's really nice to work with you and see you
working with the new girls as well so thank you.
Okay, so let's move on to the questions. So what this was one of the questions
of one of our members post and the answers that you gave so he wants to talk to
us a little bit about this Paul so what kind of model do to prepare for a photo
shoot.
So, for a lot of people, there are initial photo shoot is going to be a
completely alien environment for them.
And so you have to sort of just try and prepare yourself mentally first and
foremost.
But what I will also say is, if you are either approaching a photographer or
you have a photographer actually approach you and try and find out a little bit
about them, because sometimes.
And that's why that's where you actually find it where they're not you're
actually going to click with them because it's important to, to click on a
shoot.
And I don't mean sort of then right okay okay we've done the shoot let's go for
a drink like that but it's just purely about, can you actually get along with
this person do you feel at ease with them when you're actually shooting.
So just do a bit of sort of like checking in on them as well, ask them for
references I always suggest that to all the models I work with they should
always ask for references.
Any photographer worth their salt will not turn out and hide that from them
they will be quite prepared to actually provide references for you.
Likewise, if you want to reach out to any of the models they've worked with,
you know, make sure that you actually do that and just find out a little bit
because references can be one thing but to actually hear it from the actual
person that they shot with that seem better.
And also just make sure that you at the very beginning work out exactly what it
is that they want to shoot.
So, you know what are they actually what are they looking to shoot and where
are those images going to get used.
Because that also can be important to you as well because if it's images that
you don't want to be out there in the public domain.
So that's actually quite clear. Some photographers will ask you to sign a model
release form, but at the end of the day it's a verbal agreement between you.
And the photographer still has the copyright to the images as well so please be
aware of that.
So, just, you know, be open and upfront and ask the questions don't be don't be
don't think that you actually sort of pushing them into a corner. Ask the
questions because they're important to you.
With regards to what the actual shoot itself as I said, styling content, you
know, if you have levels that you work to those the levels you work to.
And if you get asked to go above those ones, no is no.
So stick to your guns.
And if you want to take a chaperone along because you're you're new to this or
you're having to travel to the shoots.
Again, any photographer with a salt will turn around and be okay with a chaper
one being there.
Anyone's that don't want them there. Why, why is there not what somebody there.
So just always do that.
And try and get some sort of ideas about what style and content use things like
Pinterest.
It's a great, a great portal for actually sort of getting ideas together,
putting together a mood board so you can actually see this is sort of things I
want to try and create.
If you want to have those conversations, plenty of conversations with with the
photographer don't just dive straight in comms is beforehand is very, very
important because it means that everyone knows what they stand.
And when it comes to things like the outfits, pick out outfits that you know
are going to actually compliment.
And when I say an outfit I don't just mean the actual address or the lingerie
or bikini or trousers or whatever, but also all the other bits and pieces as
well.
Because they actually can add to the actual image, the right jury, the right
shoes.
Even the right makeup as well, because not all the makeup works for every one
of those outfits, not all hairstyles will work for everyone in those outfits.
So think about these and practice at home in front of the mirror.
And just try the outfits on, lay them out in the bed, make decisions. If need
be, send the images of the outfits to the photographer beforehand and say,
these are the ones I actually want to shoot with.
I do that quite often with with the models I work with our semi images
beforehand, it gives gives me that idea in my head about what to expect when
they actually put it on.
And also, if I'm shooting in the studio, colour of the backdrop type of lights I
'm going to use with them.
So it helps then to actually make the day run a little bit smoother.
Thank you Paul. That was amazing so much useful information there and Georgia
is only the new dad to that.
As Paul was talking, literally everything that he was saying, I was like, yes,
yes, yes, and a lot of things that you've already mentioned that on my, on my
list later tips that I'm going to give.
So yeah, no, I don't have any more polls mentioned every then, so thank you.
I've ever seen your Thunder Georgia.
No, don't be silly.
Okay, let's move on to the next one then.
So, what should you expect from your photographer? So you've talked about this
a little bit, so just anything that we've missed.
So before, after, and during a shoot, what should you expect?
Okay, so any shoot, whether it's a paid shoot, or whether it's a time forward
shoot, at the end of the day you're working together.
So respect, and that goes both ways.
But in particular, the respect for the model.
So if the model is not comfortable in the pose that they're in, if they're not
happy with the way that the images are lit.
Then, speak up.
Speak up, because sometimes the photographers will just take the photographs.
They don't hear anything from the model, and they think the model's happy.
And then the model walks away and goes, "I don't like any of these. I don't
like any of these."
So you always have to speak up. When I turn around and take the photographs, I
always, as I go through it,
I actually then will show on the back of camera the images I'm actually
actually seeing,
so that the model has an opportunity to actually see what I can see.
But at the same time, can look at it and go, "I'm not comfortable with the way
my arm is, and my leg is in the net,
or the outfit the way it's holding, or my expression. Can we do that one again
?" Yes, fine, okay.
But make sure that there is respect there.
And as I say, if you don't feel respected by the photographer, there's nothing
to stop you from actually turning.
It's called a day on it and saying, "I'm not comfortable. I'm not comfortable."
Okay, safety. I mentioned that earlier on about things like, you know, if you
are new to this,
and you're travelling somewhere, and you're not sure about the location, if you
're shooting outdoors,
for example, in an urban environment, take somebody with you, because if you're
standing around,
you're not always going to be able to have your phone in your hand all the time
.
So it's always good to have somebody there to actually be a support for you as
well,
so that if it becomes that the area is in a safe, or you feel in a safe area,
you've got somebody there to actually look after you as well.
Okay, because I'll be honest with you, a lot of photographers, the first thing
they'll do is they'll grab their camera bag
before they actually look to help the model. Okay, so always try and actually
look at things like that.
If you're travelling somewhere, make sure people actually know where you're
going as well.
You're travelling from one area, and you're travelling somewhere else, and just
let a few people know,
this is where I'm going, this is where I'm going to be working with, and this
is the area I'm going to be in.
All right. When it comes to the actual shoot itself, make sure there's regular
breaks in there.
Don't be afraid to turn outside, can we take a comfort break? Can I grab a
quick drink?
Because if you're comfortable, if you're relaxed, the images will show that.
So you want to turn around and do that. You want to have breaks.
You want to just have a sit down, review some of the images you've already got.
Just ask the photographer, can we have a look through what we've got already so
far?
And then, again, that gives an opportunity for you to actually just re-engage,
look at what you've actually achieved,
what more can you actually do? And as I said, engagement and teamwork.
That's what it should be about. I always turn around and say that whenever I do
a shoot,
whether it's a time for or whether it's a paid shoot, it's a collaboration
between myself and the model.
We're both trying to get the best out of that day.
So I always look at it that way. And for me, I always look at it and say,
well, the model's actually the one that's got the harder job than me.
I stand there with the camera and just point it and go click.
The model has got the make up, the hair, the outfits I was in,
and having to do all the bits and pieces. Oh, and one other thing,
you will come away from the shoot exhausted because all that posing does take
it out of you.
So make sure you fuel up on plenty of snacks during the day.
Just to keep yourself going, bananas, fruit, the occasional custard cream bisc
uit, whatever,
just to keep yourself going, keep your sugar levels up and make sure you've got
enough energy for me.
All right. And you're quite good at sometimes being snacks with you, aren't you
?
Oh, yeah, I'll do some.
Yeah, I might actually do that when we meet ten next week, I might bring some
snacks.
Paul actually baked, so he's actually bought stuff that he's baked to.
She's gone down well.
And one other thing I was just thinking about,
the expectations from the photographer may be good to mention about editing
because some people will have different expectations.
I don't normally share any of my unedited images with any of the models without
a watermark across them.
That might sound a little bit selfish, but it's a bit like if you were doing a
painting
and you were selling that painting or giving that painting to somebody,
would you give them all the sketches beforehand? No, you wouldn't.
So it's the same with this. I try and get as much done in camera as possible
the way I want it to be.
But what I will do is I will turn around and just explain to the model that if
they want to pick out some of the ones that are raw,
then I'll see if I edited some of those ones because it could be ones that they
prefer that the art ones I picked out.
So, yeah, as I said, not everyone actually likes to edit images and some people
just like to just put them straight up onto whatever social media person myself
.
I do some editing. I don't go over the top. You're not going to end up with
skin that looks like you're plastic,
but I will turn around and actually just take out the occasional blemish you're
in there because at the end of the day, we all have them.
Yeah, thank you. Thank you for. Okay, so another question from one of our
members. So I'm worried that I don't look like a model or I won't be confident
enough to pose.
So any tips with that? I really like what you said in response to this for.
Well, it is that this definition of what is a model.
A model can be anything. That's the whole point.
And it's, it's about the way that you actually feel more than anything else and
what you want to portray.
If you want to sort of portray that you're a business woman and you'll wear a
power suit.
If you want to portray that you're a night, you know, the nightclub, you'll
wear something that's a little appropriate for that.
It's whatever it is. There is, there is no such thing as a model.
When you get, when you get dressed up to go out, you put outfits on that you
think, yeah, I look good at this.
I like this and you go out.
It's the same when it's in front of the camera.
So nobody should actually think, oh, you know, well, am I a model? Everyone can
be a model.
For all shapes, raw size, raw ages, raw, all colours or all crease, et cetera.
So there's nothing to stop anybody from actually being a model.
It's about you looking at the mirror and going, yep, I can do this.
That's the point. It's just about having that little bit of confidence.
When I take the, when I do a shoot, I'm not trigger happy.
I don't just fire image off at image, no, click, click, click, click, click,
click, click.
Because there's no point because the model doesn't know where they are.
I do help with regards to the posing.
I will turn around to sort of advise on various bits of posing.
I will turn around and explain the reason why I want them to actually pose in
that way.
If they pose in a certain position and I look at it and I go, you'll know
straight away
because I'll say, nope, don't like that.
And I'll delete it straight away off the back of the camera, done.
Because I want it to be the best ones possible.
Practice in front of mirrors, honestly.
That's the best one I would always suggest is practice in front of the mirror.
Look at how you see the celebrities, how they actually pose in front of the pap
arazzi
when they're on the red carpet.
Simple things like that.
Look at all the various different magazines that are out there.
I'm not suggesting the FHMs and all those ones, but just fashion magazines.
Look at the way they actually pose them, the light that's on them, the position
they have.
You know, make sure you arch the back, you elongate the neck as much as
possible.
Eye contact, but not always.
You don't always have to have eye contact with the camera.
But the eyes is where you're actually drawn in to first.
Because if you engage with those, then you can engage with the rest of it.
So I wouldn't worry about posing.
And also if the other girls are there as well, I came to help you.
There's nothing to stop them from trying to go in.
Move your arm, move your head, tilt that, there's nothing to stop it.
All the girls I'm sure on the day will be there to actually sort of like help
each other on.
On the other shoots I've actually done with all of the girls so far, they've
all been great.
They've all helped each other out.
They've all helped with regards to, this is how fit you should try.
Put that one on, put these shoes on, put that one on there.
Sharing bits and pieces, different bits of jewelry, sharing.
You look great now, move your arm, change this arm position.
And honestly, it was so supportive, it was great to see.
And that's what it should be about, it should be, you know, empowerment is used
an awful lot,
but it should be about that, it should be about helping each other, not putting
each other down.
It's very easy to put somebody down rather than actually build somebody up.
So, yeah, I'm sure it would be great to be honest with you.
I don't think anybody will have any fears about it.
And I never just go straight into the photographs, will always have a turn
around, a bit of a chat,
a bit of a warm up sort of thing, shake out the arms, stretch the mouth a
little bit
to make sure that you're sort of nice and relaxed in the face.
And as I said, I'll show the images that we go along so you can see what you're
guessing.
And believe me sometimes, that's all it takes is just that initial,
oh, does that what it looked like on the back of the camera?
Excellent, right, let's do more, let's do more, let's do more.
So, don't go, anybody worrying about that, honestly, please don't.
Oh, thank you Paul, yeah, and you're right, it's such a big thing when you've
got skills all around you
and you're all having fun and like I'm no expert on posing whatsoever,
but I've literally been side by side with people like just saying,
just copy me, just do what I'm doing just so they don't feel silly, you know.
Same, that's it, we've got, we think we've got put in on the next slide as well
.
So I'll come back to you, Georgia on that.
I'm sure you might have a couple more things that you want to say on that as
well.
Okay, so just just a few things.
Actually, it's funny because me and Georgia were like, okay, let's put a few,
let's put a few things about getting the best content.
What can we, what are the elements of getting the best content?
And we both wrote a list and sent it to each other and it was exactly the same
list.
So this is what we were talking about when we're thinking about getting the
best content.
And a lot of this stuff has already been covered by a lovely Paul.
Do you want to go over these, Georgia, do you want to talk about these?
Yeah, sure.
So, and obviously like Bell just said, a few of these have been mentioned, so
cloven and makeup.
And I always do this before shoots and I also, like Paul said, send pictures of
the photographer too of what else I'm thinking of because that will affect, you
know, a lot of different things on the day.
But yeah, I just like to be super prepared before the shoot just because when
you're there, there's already a lot going on and especially if you're new to it
.
So you may as well really just get as much of a pit beforehand just so you feel
more relaxed and, yeah, uncomfortable on the day.
So that's something to think about is your cloven and your makeup.
But I won't go much more into that so you've already touched on that one.
And then, secondly, the atmosphere.
So this one is like, when I first started shooting, I used to shoot like whole
time for a couple of years when I was, when I was a bit younger.
And this is something that I like I never even thought of until I got older.
I would just go there and maybe the vibe would be awful this or that and I just
, I just do it anyway because I was booked and paid for it but now I would never
even dream of shooting if I got there and it was a bad atmosphere or a bad
energy.
And for things that you can do to make the atmosphere better obviously if the
photographer is in, you know, is willing to as well as maybe you can play some
music.
You can like some incense.
You can maybe have a little dance and a little stretch and just get yourself
all ready and, you know, or loose.
But yeah, that's what I would recommend.
Have you got anything else to say on that one poll already?
No, I think I think you captured it. I always try and have music on.
Yeah.
And I don't put my music on because I'm too old.
But if the model brings along whatever they want to actually listen to some of
them, it puts them in the mood.
Good mood to sort of like have a bit of a good day, you know, and just put that
on.
And just listen to that, you know, just sort of like get lost in the moment.
And as you said, yeah, just even sort of like in between sort of like to be
moved around and so forth or just, you know, a bit of a dance around.
Get the energy going.
You know, have a bit of a laugh and a giggle.
So one thing I would stress though is if you are going to end up drinking
alcohol, take it easy on that.
Because one, it impairs judgments and two, it also, it actually shows in images
as well.
So I'm not, I'm not averse to anybody having a glass of Prosecco or a wine or
anything like that.
Don't have a problem with that whatsoever.
But bear in mind that it potentially could actually sort of show.
Yeah, definitely.
And I think that goes back to the respect as well, like have respect for the
top of that, that they're given their time.
And, you know, you don't want to get drunk and end up ruining the shoot and not
praise any good images because you just, yeah, you're just too drunk for it.
Obviously, maybe a glass of wine or whatever is nice before, if you want to,
that can help you relax, but yeah, like Paul said, just don't take it too far.
And okay, so moving on to lighting. So obviously, and, well, usually the, well,
yeah, not usually, it will be the photographer who's who's setting up the light
in, or maybe you'll be in natural light.
So, I would always say, like, be aware of the light and especially the one that
's, I don't know what it's called Paul, but like the main one that's on your key
light, the key light.
Yeah, so, for example, if the light was over here, and I was my head was here
and I was doing a pose like obviously it's going to be on the back of my head,
probably not great you want to try and bring your face and, you know, open up
to the light.
Sometimes, though, I mean, depending on what the shoot is and what you're doing
, you can be creative with the light and obviously have it light up different
parts of your or whatever else.
But usually you want to try and have your face and, you know, have your open
body towards the light so it's, and the photographer will direct you through
this too.
So, yeah, so I always consider that when I'm posing whatever like the light is
like the main, the main light you've just said what it was called sorry.
Like the key light, whatever the key light is I always in.
Yeah, I always find the light and face that way.
Like a moth.
Yeah, like a moth.
Okay, so next.
I think an angles. So, we spoke about this a little bit before but something
that we didn't mention that I wanted to mention.
And so be aware of where the camera is as well. So for example, okay so I'm
just sat like this now with my knee like this. Yeah, if I was sat like that on
the shoot.
And Paul was snapped that and you know a full picture of me like this, it
wouldn't look very good. Like, you know what I mean like you.
So it's like try not to like think about what's facing the camera so you don't
want to have like in limp like you can't even get what I'm trying to say yeah
yeah you don't want to like.
Put parts of the camera that aren't going to look good you know what I mean.
And also remember that whatever is closest to the camera of course it's going
to appear bigger.
So just remember that when you're doing your shoots so in you don't want to be
like too close or too far with different parts of your body you want to just
try and have it all in.
Yeah, have it all like show how how it should be shown not like like your elbow
like this or something like that like you want to do it to the side or whatever
else.
Does that make sense.
Yeah, I'm explaining myself very well here so because you're doing you're doing
fine Georgia. All I would say is that it's things like if you if you use the
things like your elbow or your knee.
It looks like you're missing the rest of the limb.
Exactly.
And also if you hold your hand up next to your face.
And then you move it towards the camera your hand will look bigger than your
face.
Whatever's actually closest to camera is going to look the largest.
So what you want to try and do is you want to try and make sure that you're
conscious of where you're actually placing limbs.
Now sometimes a photographer will shoot from a lower angle.
And I don't mean up the skirt I want about from a lower angle.
And by doing that you can actually make somebody look an awful lot taller.
If you actually think about if you go into any of the high street fashion
houses.
All of their mirrors that you actually look at that you go and check yourself
in.
They're actually leaning back.
They don't know the map right there all lean back.
And the intention is to make you look an awful lot taller than you are.
To make your limbs look an awful lot longer.
And it's just a trick a trick that actually used to try and make you look at it
.
And then you get home and go I didn't look like this in the store.
So that's what they actually do that for.
But it's just things like you know and one of my phrases I was using it sounds
a bit rough but is breaking limbs.
So put right angles in everywhere put triangles in so when you actually hold
your arms don't have them down at your side straight but bend them.
If you're going to sort of like have your legs out then bend the knee slightly
because straight limbs don't look great.
Yeah.
Exactly.
So you did describe it very well Georgia.
Thank you.
And another thing actually I wanted to touch on before we move on to the last
point is also it's good to ask the photographer what frame they're shooting at
because, for example, I could it could just be a frame of this and then I've
got my hands down here.
Do it all kinds of my hands and you can't even see them.
So maybe you'd want to bring your hands up here or make sure that it's in the
frame you know.
So that's something to consider as well while.
What frame the shooting at because because then obviously if they're shooting
really wide you know you've got more space to work with.
But if they're shooting in really close and you know you need to keep things
close to the body rather than so far out because it's just going to be chopped
off the frame.
And so yes you can ask the photographer just I always ask what frame are we
doing right now so I know how much space I've got to work with basically.
So yes okay we'll move on to the final the final ones which is story.
So yeah like this is these are all things that I basically learned in recent
years like when I was younger I didn't really think about this stuff but now
when I'm shooting I really love him.
Like getting into like the character and what what I'm trying to tell in the
photo like what what am I trying to put across to the audience you know whoever
's going to give you in the photo.
So even when you're getting dressed for the shoes and getting ready just put
yourself into that character of whatever it is you're going to be that day.
Like Paul said if you're going to be like a boss like a you know that a
business a business person a business lady whatever like you're going to be
wearing a powerful suit and like just be a lapper of the day and just get into
whatever character it is.
And then and then yeah just tell a story and and just just like be playful with
it as well and try not to take it too seriously.
And just yeah that's what I would say on that one.
I was just thinking there's a bit of a funny story about that one because you
remember when you were doing that photo shoot with that guy in Thailand and you
had this like beautiful big house and she was like I'm in my god ass like I'm a
goddess
and my castle and she was boy smiting me like inner character ready for the
shoot and then the first thing that the guy said when you walked in the shoot
was like you're like you know he getting it and he was like yes pretty girl in
big house.
Yeah, and I was like no it's like it's a goddess in here castle and you just
said you can even say pretty girl you just said girl in the big house.
There's not the virus and goddess in here castle but I just kept a five going
because I was all the enough enough I've so so yeah.
Time for it doesn't always have to be aligned as long as in your head. Exactly.
And the photos with a goddess.
Okay.
Okay so the next bit was just Georgia's tips but I feel like we may have had,
we may have had your tips already Georgia's anything you had.
Yeah there was a couple of them that we didn't go over but a lot of them we
already mentioned well quality mentioned a lot of them as well.
Okay so.
First my first one was be prepared obviously we've already spoke on that a
little bit so outfits here makeup and all the rest of it but also just leading
up to the shoes like I'm already preparing for the shoot next week with in
regards to what I'm eating.
You know how I'm looking after myself and my and my body and my skin and my my
spirit everything I really want to make sure I'm in the best possible in space
I could be in.
So for example, in the days leading up to the shoes if I know you said blow to
me and makes me feel like shit and I'm not going to eat pizza and the days
leading up to it you know like just be mindful of all I've got a shoe coming up
in a few days maybe for these next couple of days.
I should look after myself and my body and put it actually a little bit of
effort in to do the things that make me feel good.
Because you don't want to wake up on the day the shoot feeling bloated or you
know your your skin is not great because you're not kept yourself hydrated or
something like this.
So back to the first thing I would say is just prepare yourself in the days
leading up to it because you want to feel the best that you could feel and you
can allow yourself to do that if you just if you just plan to do that before.
And, and I wrote what do you want from the shoot and what type of pictures and
stuff did you want to create we've also kind of went over this, but it's good
to discuss with the photographer beforehand.
And what you both want out of the day so for example, if I do collaboration
shoots maybe I want a picture of me looking like a dom like a really amazing
like strong powerful picture.
And then maybe after that they'll want to try something different and we will
do something a little bit more soft or something like this.
And then we're both happy and we both we know what we both want from the day,
you know, so I think it's good to always in speak with a photographer and just
really know what you both want out of the day.
And then you've got a clear plan then a bottle and what to do.
I feel uncomfortable stretch and dance so yeah like just, I mean do whatever it
is that makes you feel good but I if the music's on and especially if I put the
music on like if it's my music.
Then I just want to like play and have fun and just like open my body up and
just feel.
Yeah, just then just feel like like happy and just feel in the moment rather
than oh I've got to do this pose and this and that and it becomes stiff you
know because the best photos I feel are the ones when when you do feel
completely comfortable and it's more like
you're just not too posed because when you are holding a position for too long
and you're too posed, I feel like it translates in the photo when it does for
me.
And so yeah just feeling comfortable as well.
And don't put too much pressure on yourself too I mean it's not the end of the
world if you come away from it and you know that you haven't got a million new
photos that you love like you know it's not.
It's not the end of the world and if you put pressure on yourself it's only
going to make the photos cannot not great to just try and enjoy it and relax
and I'm sure that they will turn out amazing you know.
Okay.
Okay so breathing I wrote this to because sometimes like I will just take a
breath and then like.
Like when I'm letting it out like I want them to take the photo because I think
that it looks good on my face you know what I mean like like the breath like
maybe it's an inhale like a.
Or like something like this I don't know it depends what the shot is.
But yeah just breathing and also not just breathing for when when they're
taking the shot but just breathing in general like if you get in a bit.
Tense or a bit and you know you're not really feeling it so much just take a
moment with yourself.
And just resent yourself and just take a breath and just bring yourself back to
the current moment and.
And yeah just yeah just remember to breathe and relax into it.
Okay.
Final point.
And is your relationship with the photographer so we've already touched on this
one as well.
And I show over the photographer recently well well two weeks ago and I was in
Thailand and he's someone that I'm friends with now and shooting with him is
like a couple of these told me a couple of things about the relationship with
the photographer.
And one thing that I felt like I really got from him is he said like work with
me and not the camera.
Because so when I did that I was almost like peering down the lens like like
trying to try to sell him the story I was telling.
And the pictures just went from being quite not great a little bit in like you
know the pictures wasn't saying enough the best to then literally as soon as I
just switched that I thought I'm not just trying to look good in front of this
thing in front of my face.
I wanted to just look through the camera and into him and and and speak to him
with my eyes and my expression and my playfulness and the pictures teams are
great so this was like a new.
I was like oh yeah like I'm not just looking at sound the lens I want to look
into the photographer and and connect with them through the lens you know.
Oh yeah that's just him.
Yeah that's my final tip.
Thank you to us that's all amazing so many amazing useful tips and it's so nice
to see you presenting that as well did it so well so thank you so much.
So girls I need to go to go and get my party soon. Okay Sammy love so lovely to
see you Paul and Paul's amazing so no one worry because he's amazing and make
you feel great so I just wanted to say.
Okay so there's an opportunity here if anybody wants to ask a question either
to Paul or Georgia and you can write it in the chat or you can put your hand up
if anyone has any questions.
I'll post it in our group afterwards I know there's a lot of people who would
be watching this back so they can fill up an opportunity to ask questions as
well but.
Yeah did you have a question.
Oh no no I thought you were trying to unmute yourself.
No no questions today.
Now she's enjoying her porridge.
Okay do you know what I think that was just so thorough but there that there
isn't any questions because you both have just gone into such detail I think
that was so so useful.
Well my if anybody wants to reach out to me you've got my details so yeah Paul
means if you want to ask any questions if you want to share any ideas etc not
problem at all.
I'll be bringing some lights with me as well as some portable lights and I use
both natural light and artificial.
So but I'm sure you know and equally you know if while we're shooting if you're
not feeling it the time that is you know you're not comfortable.
Stop at any point and you can sort of go and resent yourself etc and then we
can sort of just you know start up.
If you want to change outfits because you're then thinking I actually do not
like this outfit and just go and change and we'll start up again or if you need
to go and have a bit of a five minute sit down cup of tea never been a bit of a
natter.
Just a sort of reco you know get yourself back in the mood sort of thing let me
do that.
No pressure says you're not on the clock.
On the clock so it's not sort of you know we have to get all these down.
I don't work that way.
And it's quite a different scenario next week because you know it is a social
as well you know we do have there'll be DJs there.
You know there'll be a few different places to have photos and you can change
and wear what outfits you want and we'll all be getting together so.
We all just want to have fun don't we all of us you know Paul included everyone
that's just have fun with it and I'm sure if we have fun then we'll get some
lovely images as well.
Thank you so much everybody thank you so much Paul and Jojo just saying in the
chat wow that was very useful thanks so much for everything.
And I'm sure we'll get lots of feedback like that when people have watched it
back on the website so.
Thank you so much.
No worries.
That was amazing. Thank you so much really appreciate it we'll see you all next
week.
Yes, can't wait to meet your own Paul once the next.
Okay.
Take care guys.
Thank you.
Bye.